# **AKI GAO**

xiaoyu.akihiro.gao@gmail.com | iknowhtml.github.io | github.com/iknowhtml

#### Profile

I am a JavaScript developer with a passion for technology and innovation, in particular the Web and Blockchain. I offer three years of experience in full stack web application development from conception through delivery of elegant and maintainable solutions. My expertise ranges from designing and implementing responsive and user-friendly web-based UX/UIs to architecting and developing modular, scalable and fault-tolerant back end infrastructures. Specifically, I specialize in web application development using the React and Node is ecosystems. I also have experience with Blockchain/DLT technologies and am actively involved its development and industry. My personal mission is to use technology and entreprenership to create a more compassionate and humancentric future by empowering people to connect more meaningfully and reducing social and economic inequality.

## Education

Skills

#### The University of Virginia: School of Engineering and Applied Science (SEAS)

Computer Engineering & Electrical Engineering

#### August 2016

# Languages:

• JavaScript, TypeScript, Shell (Bash)

## UX/UI and Front End Technologies and Tools:

• Sketch, HTML, CSS, React, Redux, Redux-Saga/Thunk, React/Reach Router, CSS Modules, PostCSS, Storybook

#### Blockchain Technologies:

• Ethereum, Solidity, Web3.js, Ethers.js, Truffle, Ganache, Metamask, Remix, Geth, Infura

#### Development and Testing Tools:

Agile (Scrum/Kanban), Git, NPM, Yarn, Webpack, Babel, Mocha,
Chai, Sinon

#### Back End and Database Technologies:

• Node.js, Express, Helmet, GraphQL, Apollo, MongoDB, MySQL

#### Infrastructure and DevOps Technologies:

Apache, Nginx, Docker, Jenkins, Travis, Terraform, Packer, AWS,
Azure, Google Cloud

## Work Experience

#### Blockchain Web Application Development Consultant - Freelance/Contracting

February 2018 - Present

- Provides services to clients to architect and develop front end and back end applications for Blockchain-based platforms.
- Also provides consultations to determine viability of Blockchain use cases and conceptualization of decentralized business models based on tokenization and distributed ledgers.
- Specializes in rapid prototyping of performant and user-friendly front end applications to interface with Blockchain back ends, as well as scalable hybrid back end solutions that utilize both traditional database systems and Blockchain.
- Developed solutions and provided technical capabilities for early stage Blockchain start ups across a wide range of industries including Food Supply Chain, Healthcare and Video Game Asset Management.

#### Alluminate - Javascript & Blockchain Developer

October 2017 - February 2018

- Provide high-level technology expertise and development capabilities for in-house and consulting work ranging from UX/UI to smart contract development.
- Designed, developed and maintained the company's homepage as well as the landing page for several products.
- Core development member of the CryptoPets platform, an Ethereum-based game platform for collecting and battling digital pets developed in partnership with Arcade Distillery.
- Aided in smart contract design, as well as audited smart contracts for correctness.
- Developed in-house development and testing environment using Web3, Docker and Geth.

### Booz Allen Hamilton - Technologist

May 2017 - November 2017

- U.S. Treasury Proof of Concept Blockchain Application July 2017 August 2017
  - Developed a proof of concept Blockchain application for the U.S. Treasury to replace existing payment infrastructure between Government organizations.
  - Application built with a JavaScript stack (React/Redux and Node.js) and deployed to Azure Cloud.
  - Smart contracts written in Solidity and deployed to Microsoft's Blockchain network.
  - Led development efforts across the stack, and architected the front end, back end and deployment pipeline, as well as the cloud infrastructure for the project in a small team of developers in an Agile environment using Kanban.
  - Acted as defacto Product Owner and Scrum Master to translate requirements from the stakeholder, and to convert requirements into tasks to be distributed among team members.
  - Participation, expertise and leadership in project led to conversion of project from a Proof of Concept work into a full-fledged proposal for a contract bid.
- FDA Health Blockchain Platform Investment September 2017 November 2017
  - Architected and bootstrapped the front end for the FDA Health Blockchain Platform Investment Project.
  - Application designed in Sketch and built in React.
  - Led front end development efforts, including designing the UX/UI, implementing application interface and logic, and providing high level guidance to other developers.